Hi everybody, I'm John Kuryaku and
welcome back to the briefing room. We
have a lot to go over today. I know I
say that all the time, but my goodness,
it was a busy weekend and first before
we get to the news, I just want to say
again how grateful I am, genuinely
sincerely grateful to each and every one
of you. We could not do this without
your support and the growth has been
absolutely stupendous. I can't believe
it. Also, we had our first Q&A episode
released on Saturday. You guys asked
such great questions. Please keep them
coming so that we can do them in our
next Q&A episode. Today on the show, we
have a lot to get to. Who is really
behind the unbelievable migrant crisis
in in Seut, Spain? We'll get to the
political scandal that could turn Ohio
blue, maybe temporarily. And finally,
it's election day in Michigan today and
Apac might get its biggest embarrassment
yet. We'll talk about the election
happening between an Apackedback
Democrat named Haley Stevens versus a
more DSA aligned Democrat Abdul Asai.
So, first let let's talk about Seut.
Roughly 60,000
would be migrants crossed from Morocco
into Seuta, the Spanish enclave on the
northern coast of Africa. Now, this is
important because most people actually
don't know that Spain has these two
little teeny tiny just minuscule little
patches of land in North Africa
surrounded by what is Morocco. So, if
you've watched these videos, you've
probably noticed this little thing. It's
a little bit strange. You see the
straight of Gibralar there. You see
Spain proper to the to the north,
Morocco, which of course is in North
Africa to the south. But that little
enclave called Seuta, and then farther
down the coast, there are other little
teeny tiny Spanish enclaves. Now, these
of course are remnants of colonial times
and the Moroccans don't like it. The
Spaniards do like it and uh it's an
ongoing problem. Well, Moroccan security
forces,
as you see in this video, appear to be
waving people in off of trucks. We've
heard firstirhand accounts suggesting
that Moroccan border guards effectively
just stood down as thousands of people
began moving towards Spanish territory.
This is not something that happens on
its own. So on this show, we're looking
at who decided not to stop them. Could
this happen again? And what are the odds
that something similar happens, let's
say, right here in the United States?
Because there's a much bigger fight
underneath this migrant crisis involving
Spain, Morocco, Algeria, the United
States, and potentially Israel. So
before we start talking about it, let's
take a look at a recap. This is by the
Wall Street Journal. JB, please run that
clip.
>> This is the moment hundreds of
immigrants crossed into Suta, a Spanish
territory in North Africa.
>> The mass crossings coincided with the
arrival of tens [music] of thousands of
migrants who swam into the enclave over
the past week. Authorities estimate that
at least 50,000 people streamed into
Ciota, a place that only has about
84,000 residents. Spain's government
said it had reached a tentative
agreement with Morocco to return those
who had entered. My colleague Benois
Fukon traveled to Siota on August 1st.
>> The Spanish government said yesterday
that everything was pretty much under
control and everyone had returned home
in Morocco. And you can see the crowd
behind me. You can see the police behind
me. Clearly, there's still some action.
Actually, I've seen also a lot of people
living in the crowd that was just
detained. So, obviously a lot of
military deployments, a very surreal
place, very quiet, but at the same time,
lots of armored vehicles, maning
camouflage, not a normal situation for
that city, which I'm sure the
unprecedented mass crossing has ignited
fears of a much broader immigration
crisis and raised questions about what
prompted it in the first place. The
sudden influx of migrants came after
Spain's Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez's
recent visit to Algeria, a country which
has long rivaled Morocco for influence
in the region. Some analysts believe
that the crossings were orchestrated by
the Moroccan government. The influx also
follows a recent change in Spanish law.
Previously, authorities could
immediately turn most people back, but a
July ruling has made it harder to return
immigrants if they arrive by sea. While
Prime Minister Sanchez has taken a much
more lenient approach to immigration
than many other European leaders, he
described the crossings as an attack and
a violation of Spain's territorial
sovereignty.
Okay, so a lot to unpack here.
According to the Spanish government, as
of this morning, most of the migrants
have now either been expelled, returned
to Morocco, or left voluntarily. So
these 60,000 or so that came in one day
are all gone.
There appears to have been a huge amount
of misinformation circulating beforehand
on social media, particularly the idea
that migrants who reached Seota would
simply be able to stay. They would be
welcomed in Spain, given citizenship, a
lot of them thought, and eventually be
free to travel around Europe and just
resettle anywhere they they wanted. This
is what was circulating on Facebook and
and Instagram. Listen to this interview
with a migrant who says he came to Spain
to Seut because of this misinformation
on social media.
>> All these people have been told that
they're not going to be able to get
asylum here. So, they're being turned
around and sent back right there.
>> Look at
what the police have told us.
Everyone, they're making everybody
leave.
But some people here in in
go to
>> you can see but most of them are walking
this way because the police and the
military have forced them to leave. The
military says that they're not letting
people stay that you have to go back.
>> What about if many people stay? No
problem.
>> So your hope is that you'll be able to
stay here?
>> Yeah, there's no problem.
So, you read a news article that said
that if you came here, you could claim
asylum and live in Spain. And you read
that and then you decided to swim over.
>> They say Spain has opened the door.
>> It said Spain has opened the door. This
was on social media
>> on what on Twitter or Instagram or
>> Facebook. Everyone want to be here.
>> Why don't you want to go home to
Morocco?
>> No, no, no. Morocco.
>> No, no, no,
>> no.
>> Morocco.
>> There's no money in Morocco.
>> Ah, easy.
>> If you have a family, children like
that, you can be happy all the life.
>> Do you have a family?
>> Yeah.
>> And my mother, but you should to be do
something to live a good life.
>> So, you really want to leave Morocco.
You don't care where you go
anywhere. Just Turkey. You just want to
be able to leave Morocco.
>> And why is that? Why do you want to
leave Morocco so badly?
Yeah. See,
somebody put out disinformation,
misinformation,
saying that the socialist government of
Pedro Sanchez had just opened the door
and you see the shock on the faces of
these wouldbe migrants. The doors open.
Spanish citizenship. Everybody's free to
come. And that just wasn't the case. So
the question then is why?
Not even how. There are a thousand
different ways that this could have
happened. But but why did it happen? So
early on in the hours after this thing
began,
a lot of people pointed the finger at
Israel because Spain has been probably
the single most vocal anti-Israel
country in Western Europe. Spain and
Ireland. and that the Spanish, I'm
sorry, the the uh the Israelis who are
close to the Moroccans, they have
diplomatic relations and good good
relations.
The Israelis talk the Moroccans into
just letting people leave Morocco and
flood into Seut. I'm not sure that
that's true. I think that the Israelis,
you know, probably got a kick out of
this, but I think this was specific to
Morocco. I think the Moroccans did this
on their own for a completely different
reason. It doesn't have anything to do
with Israel.
I think the Moroccans did this because
they're furious at Sanchez
for
having close relations with Algeria.
Morocco and and Algeria hate each other.
They've always hated each other. And
they're rivals for,
let's call it, primacy in North Africa.
Algeria is bigger. It's more important.
It's more powerful. It's just as poor,
but it's very powerful politically.
Sanchez went to uh went to Algeria uh
for an official visit on July 20th. The
Moroccan King Muhammad was upset and
angry and decided to sort of throw a
wrench into the works. I think that's
what happened. But the fallout is going
to be very significant. Let me tell you
what's happening while the legacy media
sleeps. This could be the biggest story
of the decade and you won't hear a word
about it from the traditional talking
heads. I spent years inside the US
government. If that experience taught me
one thing, it's this. Pay attention to
what governments do, not what they say.
So, watch what China is doing. They shut
down paper gold trading at four of their
largest banks. Same move, same day. They
keep physical gold wide open, build a
new settlement system through Hong Kong,
and expanded their vault capacity
tenfold.
The official explanation is that they're
protecting retail traders from
volatility. I've read a lot of official
explanations in my life. This one
doesn't hold up. China's trade surplus
about $1.2 trillion
a year. Their gold imports about 940
tons a year. Divide one by the other and
you get what gold would have to be worth
if China ever pays its bills in gold
instead of dollars. $38,000
an ounce. That's just simple math. And
what is our government doing while China
prepares? It's printing trillions in
interest on debt that they'll never
repay. Every dollar they print out of
thin air makes the dollars you saved
your whole life worth less. Nobody voted
for that tax, but everybody pays it,
especially the savers and retirees who
did everything right. I've seen how this
works from the inside. The people in
charge will not send you a warning
letter. That's why I want to tell you
about my friends at American Alternative
Assets. They help everyday Americans
protect their retirement with physical
gold and silver. And they're one of the
most trusted precious metals companies
in the country. A+ rated with the Better
Business Bureau. over 50,000 Americans
served and a 100% US-based team. They
put together a free report called The
Day Money Changes Forever. Inside,
you'll discover why gold could be headed
to $38,000
an ounce and the easiest way to protect
your life savings before the crowd
catches on.
A real US-based specialist walks you
through it. No pressure. Get your free
copy at johnlovesgold.com
or call 888G053.
Don't wait for the official explanation.
By then, it's already happened. The
Spanish government right now is on the
brink of collapse. Not just because of
what happened in Seuda, but because
about a month ago,
this government, which is a socialist
government, announced that it would
legalize
120,000 here to for undocumented
migrants, all almost all of whom have
come from North Africa.
Well, you you can't do that. You can't
just open the floodgates and and expect
to be able to provide
housing, food, water, jobs, medical
care, education
to anybody who happens to be able to
make it across your border. I mean, it's
it's a noble idea to want to help the
poor, the the downtrodden, etc. I come
from an immigrant family myself, but
it's not practical. You can't you can't
afford it.
So the damage has been done. Spain is
furious. Not just the Spanish
government. The Spanish people are
furious. The prime minister, as I said,
leads this left-leaning government that
has generally taken a more sympathetic
approach toward migrants. His government
insists that its policies did not cause
this surge
and that the same thing could have
happened under a right-wing government.
But I think politically he's done. Spain
says the immediate crisis has subsided.
They've expelled everybody. Although
videos circulating on social media
suggest that some migrants apparently
remain in Seuta. And Europe's right-wing
parties are having a field day.
In Britain, Nigel Farage, the leader of
the Reform UK party, warned that the
migrants entering Seota would make their
way toward the French northern coast and
then onward to the UK by crossing the
English Channel. Entirely possible. The
deputy leader of the French National
Front Party posted, quote, "By
regularizing hundreds of thousands of
undocumented immigrants, Spain's
socialist prime minister, Pedro Sanchez
has opened the doors of Europe to all
dangers." Unquote.
Of course, some of this is political
opportunism. We we would expect that.
But the real question is what made
Morocco essentially just let 60,000
people cross the border with no check.
And I think that's where this becomes
more interesting. Think about this.
Morocco potentially let dozens of it of
its citizens die swimming into Seut
purely to show that it can just mess
with Spain whenever it wants to.
That's an insane weapon to use against
another country. As you heard, Morocco
has let this happen to Spain once
before. This was back in 2021. It seems
like Spain made a terrible mistake
letting Morocco control the flow of
migrants into SEA, especially given
political differences between the two
countries. It looks like they did it
again over frustration
over Spain's relationship with Algeria.
But there are even more concerns that
another country was involved. As I said,
and you can guess, the fingers are
pointing at Israel. You'll remember,
Israel and the US are not happy with
Spain. Spain has not been letting the US
use Spanish airspace for military
strikes. And the Spanish people have
been one of the most outspoken groups
criticizing Israel over its actions in
Gaza. As Spain criticizes Israel for
being an occupying colonial power,
Israel has been trolling Spain for its
colonial settlements in Africa like
Seuta.
Spain was given those territories in
treaties more than 400 years ago. So a
little less recent than Israel laid
claims to places like Rafa and the West
Bank. But you can see Israel's point.
So far, I have not seen any direct
evidence linking Israel to this migrant
surge, but it definitely seems that
Israeli conservatives are loving it.
Israeli Defense Minister Bengavir posted
in Spanish, quote, "My congratulations
to the president of the government of
Spain," he meant Prime Minister Pedro
Sanchez, for his profound commitment to
welcoming immigration and quote human
diversity unquote. But then something
else caught my attention. Friend of the
show, Thomas Massie, posted, "As of just
recently, it's official." This is the
post. As of recently, it's official US
policy that we oppose Spain's colonies
in Morocco. And we even call it an
occupation.
How the heck did that get into a US law?
We even gave $40 million to the Moroccan
government. Like I said, no direct
evidence yet, but I would not be
surprised at all if USIsraeli
intelligence were aware of this and then
just stood by and didn't stop it or
didn't warn the Spanish. That would make
more sense to me.
Um, you know, at the CIA, you've got an
army of analysts, right? These are
supposed to be well what John Kennedy
called the best and the brightest people
who are experts in their field. And
you've got a group of people just
watching issues like this. So did the
CIA know that this was going to happen
or that the preparations were being made
for this to happen? Of course they did.
They didn't act.
I wouldn't actually have expected them
to act because it doesn't really impact
US interests. And if the if the idea is
that the fallout is going to embarrass
Spain, okay. And if you're Donald Trump,
who cares? Who cares if if if it
embarrasses Spain?
Hearing about a migrant surge caused by
60,000 or 120,000 migrants in Spain
previously receiving citizenship. The
question for the United States is then,
could that happen here? That's really
what you want your analysts to think
about. Could this happen here? We
obviously have a very different border
situation, but there's something related
with with temporary protected status,
TPS, for certain migrant groups in the
US, particularly Haitian migrants
in Springfield, Ohio. I want to talk
about this for a second. Right now, that
group is in a very weird kind of limbo.
Check Check out this clip.
>> This is really humiliating. There are
certain way you treat somebody, that
person become like an animal.
>> MS Now has exclusive reporting that at
least two Haitians living here in
Springfield, Ohio, who've seen their
temporary protected status expire have
been fitted with ankle monitors by ICE.
>> There is a sense of fear. Fear about
today and fear about tomorrow. [music]
>> And many more have been receiving this
letter to their homes. The letter gives
them short notice to report to an ICE
facility here in Ohio. And in that ICE
facility, they have a meeting with an
immigration officer. The Haitians tell
MS Now they're presented with two
difficult options. Either get detained
[music] on the spot or be fitted for an
ankle monitor until they can show up for
a court appearance. And all of this is
having severe psychological
ramifications on the Haitian community
here in Springfield, Ohio of about
12,000 people. I'm worried like
a lot about self harm and um strokes
because some of them tell me they got
that letter and they haven't slept.
>> They're not only crying like because of
this letter but they know like when they
get deported what they are what they
going to be like facing when they go
back to Haiti. I would call it a
butchery the way I see things down
there. Like I I think it's really bad.
>> Now, all of this is part of President
Trump's mass deportation campaign
promise. We reached out to DHS about
these ankle monitors. They didn't
acknowledge them directly and instead
opted to quote the song Closing Time by
the band SemiSonic, writing to the
Haitian community that it's closing
time, which means you don't have to go
home, but you can't stay here.
Yeah, ankle monitors. The Trump
administration's argument articulated by
Steven Miller is pretty straightforward.
Temporary protected status is supposed
to be exactly that, temporary. So TPS
exists to protect people who cannot
safely return to their home countries
because of extraordinary conditions,
things like armed conflict, natural
disasters, or other temporary
catastrophes. We have thousands of
Ukrainians here in the US on TPS status
right now and hundreds of thousands of
Haitians after the 2012 earthquake. But
there's a difficult problem. What do you
do when the conditions in that home
country are no safer than they were
decades ago? Often times the US is
largely to blame for that country being
a hell hole. and and revoking TPS
amounts to a death sentence for many of
these people. Haiti is a case in point.
It is well documented that the Clintons,
Bill Clinton as president, Hillary
Clinton as Secretary of State under
Barack Obama wrecked Haiti. They wrecked
it. Couple that with a catastrophic
earthquake
and you have a situation where it's just
not safe to live.
Armed roving gangs control Haiti right
now. And see, you have people like the
the folks you just saw in that clip who
have been here for quite a while on
temporary status who just can't safely
go back. They're likely to be killed.
What do you do? The TPS is expired.
They're not officially refugees. They
haven't applied for citizenship or green
cards. So, what do you do? What is the
government strategy here? When clearly
you can't house everyone from a messed
up country who wants to come. So, how
many do you take? And of the ones that
you take, how long do you allow them to
remain?
I'll give you another example.
Let's say you are an Afghan
who volunteered to be a translator for
the US Army, right? You worked for the
army or the CIA or the American embassy
or whatever for 10 years, 20 years and
then the Americans lose to the Taliban
and pull out of the country. Well,
you're going to lose your head.
Everybody in your family is going to be
arrested.
So, you come to the United States under
TPS
and then what? And then you risk the
American government sending you back to
Taliban controlled Afghanistan.
This is a problem that's not going to
end today, whether it's in Springfield,
Ohio, or in Suta, Spain, or in Morocco
or anywhere else.
And it's going to be one of the primary
political issues
in every country in Western Europe.
We're going to come back to it again.
Have you ever wondered what it feels
like to shoot with the same precision
tech used by US special forces? Well,
good news. After years of research and
development, MCG Tactical just dropped
something incredible. The Stinger combat
site. This is not your average red dot.
Using holographic technology, once
reserved for elite military and law
enforcement, the Stinger delivers
crystalclear precision, so accurate you
could hit a dime at 300 yards without
even trying. This is the exact same
level of technology used by the pros.
But here's the twist. Most sites like
this go for 600 bucks or more, and
people happily pay it. But right now,
through an exclusive deal with MCG
Tactical, you can get this Milspec site
for under $200.
And it gets better. For my listeners,
you're getting 67% off and they're
covering the shipping costs.
Seriously, this is something you are not
going to want to miss. Just scan the QR
code or go to mcgac.com/jjohsting
to get yours today. The only catch,
supply is tight and these things are
flying off the shelves. So if you want a
site built for the best, now is your
shot. Grab yours before they have to
shut down orders. That is
mcgac.com/johsting.
There is a scandal taking place in Ohio
within the Republican party
and it's going to be something that I
think most political observers and
reporters are going to focus on. And
besides that, how many members of
Congress are being blackmailed for being
closeted and gay?
So, there's this scandal in Ohio that
could, and I don't say this lightly,
singlehandedly
make it so that Republicans lose a seat
in the US Senate, the US House, and the
Governor's Mansion.
This is Ohio. Ohio used to be a purple
state. It's not purple anymore. It's
red. But Democrats could sweep in Ohio.
And these are all seats that Republicans
just cannot afford to lose. At the
center of this is a Republican
congressman by the name of Max Miller.
Max Miller is married to Emily Moreno.
Emily Moreno is the daughter of Ohio
Senator Bernie Moreno. And the
allegations against Max Miller are
horrifying.
As reported in the New York Times, Emily
Moreno, the daughter of Senator Bernie
Moreno, has said that Miller scalded her
chest and her stomach by throwing hot
water from a skillet at her. He held a
gun to her head. He pushed her against
the wall and slammed her head. And he
fractured their 2-year-old daughter's
collarbone and bruised her shoulder.
They even had to file a restraining
order against the congressman and Emily
Moreno's attorney because he grabbed the
attorney in court.
If my son-in-law laid a finger on my
daughter or my granddaughter,
I'd wreck his life in more ways than
one. Well, Emily Moreno's father, as I
said, is a US senator. And Bernie Moreno
finally broke his silence on his
daughter's abuse two years after the
allegation surfaced this week, writing
on Twitter. This is what he said. Quote,
"As he has admitted privately, Max
Miller needs serious psychological help.
He is a danger to my daughter and I hold
my breath every minute he has custody of
my granddaughter. If there are any basic
standards of character required to hold
elected office, Max Miller fails them.
He should not serve in the House of
Representatives."
Okay, think of it this way, too.
We're in August.
The Ohio primary was last May.
Max Miller won his primary uncontested
and his own father-in-law,
a US senator, has just come out and said
that he's not equipped to be a member of
the House of Representatives. So, you're
probably wondering, why was this man so
delayed in speaking out against his
daughter's alleged abuser? Sure, he
might not want to influence an ongoing
court case. All right, I understand
that. But there's also the possibility
of blackmail.
You'll like this. Before Moreno became a
US senator, Miller messaged him this
threat. Quote, "People are about to get
to know you better than your wife does.
Take that however you like." Unquote.
Here's what he post here's what he
posted on his Twitter account.
Quote, "Hi,
looking for young guys to have fun with
while traveling.
reads a caption on the photo list
profile under the username Nardo19672.
That's according to an Associated Press
review of records made public through a
massive and wellpublished data breach of
the website.
Mareno didn't deny it. He blamed the
account on an intern in his office and
claimed that the account was created as
a prank. The intern even made the
following statement. quote, "I am
thoroughly embarrassed by an aborted
prank I pulled on my friend and former
boss, Bernie Mareno, nearly two decades
ago."
This intern then donated $6,599
to Mareno's campaign, according to
campaign finance records.
Is Marino closeted gay? Who knows? Who
cares?
But it's all part of this bigger
scandal.
You know, it makes one wonder too how
many politicians,
senior politicians, national
politicians,
do you think are closeted in some way
and are being blackmailed for it? You
know, back in the 80s when I was in
college,
two Democratic congressmen at the same
time were outed. Congressman Barney
Frank, who just recently died, he was a
Democrat of Massachusetts, and
Congressman Gary Studs, who was also a
Democrat from Massachusetts.
Um there was another uh congressman, a
Republican from Mississippi, John
Henson.
So Barney Frank was um
having a a gay affair with a guy who
turned out to be a prostitute. Frank
apparently didn't know that he was a
prostitute and allowed the guy to move
into his house on Capitol Hill. And when
Frank was at work being a congressman,
the guy was turning tricks in the
congressman's house. He got outed.
The guy uh admitted that he was a
congressman.
Frank had to admit that he was gay.
Nobody cared.
Gary Studs, however, was having sex with
underage male pages,
16 year olds.
Believe it or not, he was reelected and
was never charged with a crime.
>> [gasps]
>> Henson was caught receiving a
from his chief of staff, his male chief
of staff, in a house bathroom.
Uh he his career did not survive the
scandal, but this kind of thing happens
all the time. Look at uh former Senator
uh Mccclure from Idaho who uh was caught
doing a toetap gay code in a men's room
in Minneapolis airport. His his defense
was that he had a wide stance when he
was using the bathroom and uh was just
tapping his toes randomly. It wasn't a
code that he wanted oral from the guy in
the next stall. His wife stuck with him.
The most important thing here is that
the family and their daughter
are going to be okay. That's the
important thing. But the political
fallout from this is going to be huge.
Bernie Morano was was behind Democrat
Sherid Brown, a former senator in Fox
News polling recently, just a week ago.
He could get dragged down from this for
looking completely spineless as his
daughter is being allegedly, you know,
beaten up and burned and abused. And Max
Miller could cost this House district
for Republicans as well. This was a safe
Republican district. Donald Trump won
this district. Ohio has become a deep
red state with Trump at the top of the
ticket. But right now, you have Vivic
Ramaswami. Remember him?
He He's the Republican nominee for
governor of Ohio. The conventional
wisdom was that he was just going to
walk away with this and win big, but he
got booed off the stage recently. Take a
look at this crazy clip. The
>> truth of the matter is, you know, no
matter what happens in whichever
direction we go, people, my generation
will have already made it. We're going
to be fine. It's going to be your
generation.
You're a political creaty
turvy politically. It's it's the
craziest thing. As I said, Vivic
Ramoswami, you might remember, ran for
president a couple years ago. Young guy,
very very bright, very conservative.
He looked to be one of the faces,
the new faces of the Republican party.
He didn't do well in the presidential
primary, but he endorsed Donald Trump
early on. Trump seemed to like him and
he decided to go back to Ohio and run
for governor. And as I said, everybody
believed he was just going to walk right
into the governor's mansion. This was
supposed to be a friendly crowd.
And he was literally booed off the
stage.
Well, a poll conducted by a Republican
firm this week has Max Miller five
points behind his Democratic opponent
right now. 41%
of voters view him unfavorably and only
25% view him favorably. And that's with
the Democrats having spent zero dollars
attacking Miller's reputation. No
negative ads from the Democrats at all.
What they do is they play these
horrifying 911 calls, playing the audio
of Miller that he was using needles to
inject testosterone in his office and
all the other weird details
that keep coming out about him.
You know, looking back,
I think George Santos knew something
that the rest of us didn't know.
>> You, sir, are a crook. I know I should
direct my comments to the chair. I yield
back.
My colleague wants to come up here, call
me a crook. Same colleague who's accused
of being a woman beater.
Are we Are we really going to ignore the
facts that we all have past and we all
have the media coming out against us on
a daily basis? I can go and read about
all my colleagues. I'm not going to
stand here to smear them. I'm not going
to stand here and use the time I have to
say ill things about my colleagues. I
refuse to stoop to that level. George
Santos.
George Santos who went to prison for
being a crook. He was pardoned by Donald
Trump and uh and he's out now. He's
actually on Cameo doing lots of cameos.
I'm proud to say that I beat his record.
He was the number one most popular Cameo
person ever until John got to Cameo.
Anyway,
what makes politicians keep running for
office when the evidence against them is
beyond damning?
If I were a politician who beat the hell
out of his wife,
scalded her with hot water, beat my
two-year-old to the point where I broke
her collar bone,
may have been on a gay cruising website.
Who knows? What in God's name would make
me run for Congress?
Narcissism.
sociopathy.
It's kind of a nice system we've given
ourselves, isn't it? I spent my career
in the CIA. I know exactly how easy it
is to find someone when you have their
name and just a little bit of patience.
And here's what should scare you these
days. You don't need to be a spy to do
it. Your name, your home address, your
phone number, details about your family.
It's all sitting out there online,
compiled by data brokers, and sold to
anyone with a credit card. I've made my
fair share of enemies over the years,
and since going public on the CIA's
torture program, I've got a lot more
strangers who know who I am. So, safety
and security aren't abstract to me.
They're daily concerns. All that
personal data floating around the
internet has real world consequences.
And honestly, most people have no idea
how exposed they are. That's why I
personally use Delete Me. Delete Me is a
subscription service that removes your
personal information from hundreds of
data broker websites. You sign up, you
tell them exactly what information you
want taken down, and their experts
handle it from there. They send you
regular personalized privacy reports
showing what they found, where they
found it, and what they removed. And
it's not a one-time thing. Delete Me is
always working in the background,
constantly monitoring and removing the
information that you don't want out
there. In plain terms, they do the hard
work of wiping yours and your family's
personal information off these broker
sites. For someone like me, that peace
of mind is worth a lot. Take control of
your data and keep your private life
private by signing up for Delete Me now
at a special discount for our listeners
today. Get 20% off your Delete Me plan
when you go to joindeleteme.com/jkbr
and use promo code jkbr at checkout. The
only way to get 20% off is to go to
joindeleteme.com/jkbr
and enter code jkbr at checkout. Again,
that's joindeme.com/jkbr
code jkbr. Well, today is primary
election day in the state of Michigan,
and I have to say this is one of the
most fascinating races I've seen in a
very long time. I'm talking about the
Democratic primary for US Senate. You
have a mainstream moderate Democrat
named Haley Stevens. She's backed by
Apac,
backed by the big labor unions, and
backed by big well-funded corporate
packs. She's running against a
Democratic Socialist of Americabacked
Democrat named Abdul Asai. I want to
start this by telling you about 6 months
ago, I went to a fundraiser at a
friend's house for Abdul Ased and I had
never heard of this guy. He talked about
health care, health care, health care.
He's a medical doctor, a PhD,
and single-handedly built Michigan's
health care system. I was so impressed
by him that I sent his campaign $100. So
there, you know, my bias. Um, with that
said, the winner of this primary is
going to face Republican Mike Rogers,
who's running again after narrowly
losing the Senate race in 2024 to Alyssa
Slackin, a former CIA colleague of mine.
This is a real test of electability for
for the Democratic establishment.
The the politics this year, at least
among Democrats, are favoring DSA
related candidates. We've seen DSA
candidates win five congressional
primaries already, upsetting at least
three incumbents.
Real lefty candidates running in swing
states. Well, Michigan's a swing state.
The latest polls, and there are a lot of
them, show Alied
kicking her butt, Haley Stevens butt,
just crushing her
um by double digits. According
[clears throat] to an Emerson College
poll,
uh Stevens trails, I'll say it by 15
percentage points among likely voters.
She only received a majority of ballots
from voters ages 60 and older out of the
six different age groups that were
tested.
And this is a quote from the the firm's
executive director. There is a clear age
divide in the Democratic primary. Voters
under 50 break for Al sayed by 42
percentage points 67 to 25 and that gap
tightens among voters in their 50s to a
12point lead and voters over 60 flip to
Stevens by a 14-point margin 53 to 39.
Establishment Democrats usually get to
argue that the centrist candidate is
more electable in the general election
because they appeal to independents and
to moderate Republicans. But this is one
of the first times where it seems like
that really is not the case. It's a
question of will undecided voters in
Michigan go for someone left-wing
with a last name like Alsed, he's his
parents are from Egypt. And will Donald
Trump's voters avoid voting in the US
Senate race like they did in 2024? A lot
of them, it's not that they flip and
switch Democrat,
it's that they just stay home and don't
vote at all.
Uh, I want to show you a couple of clips
that are fascinating to me in this case.
The first is Haley Stevens. She probably
wishes at this point that she had taken
this back. Let's run this first clip.
>> And in the United States Congress,
I will continue to fight for the people
of Israel. I will continue to fight for
Israel's existence.
Israel comes to me in my dreams. I see
Israel's future. And I know that Israel
will continue to exist for the Jewish
people.
>> Why doesn't Michigan come to her in her
dreams?
Why, if elected to the Senate, will she
not go to fight for the people of
Michigan?
Right? And remember, Michigan has the
largest Muslim population in America.
So why would she say something like
this? Now, conversely, Abdullah sayed
has his own problems. He recently
appeared on MS Now and uh and was
pressed on some of these issues. Let's
go to that clip.
>> Has been largely and loudly populist,
but also anti-Zionist.
And you've sort of married those two
things, equating funding for Israel with
underfunding healthcare, for example.
Um, are you worried that that framing
juxtaposing the Jewish funding for the
Jewish state against the needs of, in
your own words, our own people echoes an
old anti-semitic trope? Let me just be
very, very clear. You know who benefits
from guaranteed healthcare in this
country? Jewish Americans. The idea that
somehow we are going to use the spectre
of anti-semitism to defend what a
foreign government is doing actually has
does a deep disservice to the well-being
of Jewish Americans in this country.
Judaism and the Jewish people are a
light unto the world. Beautiful faith,
beautiful people. The contributions that
they've made to this country alone are
staggering. And I'm looking forward to
standing with the Jewish community
against anti-semitism. After all,
anti-semitism and Islamophobia are one
in the same. And we need to take them
on. But we cannot sit idly by and ask
why is it that our $3.3 billion dollars
a year at baseline is used to fund
apartheid at baseline genocide over the
last several years a war we have no
business fighting with the attempt to
annex the southern part of a neighboring
country and then wonder why our kids
schools look like they did 50 years ago.
The reality of this
>> respectfully you haven't made that same
trade-off argument with regards to other
items in the US's $800 billion.
You just don't cover it. That's No, no,
no. I have You just don't cover it. I'll
say the same thing about the money we
send to Egypt, which is where my my
family comes from. So, if you want to go
ahead and call me anti- Egyptian, go
ahead and do that. But the reality is is
that on principle, I don't think we
should be sending unconditional foreign
military aid to any government because
none of us actually pay our tax
>> or on principle then are you against
ethnreligious states at large?
>> On principle, I absolutely am.
>> Sure. Now, uh
There's a lot to say here. Israel is a
democratic socialist state. This is
something I think most Americans don't
understand. Israel has has a robust
welfare system. If you are Jewish and
you want to immigrate to Israel, you get
everything for free. You get a free
apartment. You get free furniture. You
get free medical care. Everything's
free.
Well, it's because we we pay for that.
We send billions and billions of dollars
to Israel every year so that Israel can
have a welfare state. Now, if that's
something American voters want, okay,
God bless. If it's something that you
don't want,
then you have to express that to your
political figures.
Mike Rogers, though, Mike Rogers, former
congressman, former I believe he was the
chairman of the uh of the House uh
intelligence committee. I I may be wrong
on that, but anyway, Mike Rogers left
the House, ran for the Senate, lost, is
running for the Senate again. He polls
very well against Elsed. He polls less
well less well against um Haley uh
Stevens.
But Mike Rogers came out with an AI ad
saying that Aldo sayed
is [laughter]
a Trojan horse not for Islam but for
communism. Check out this ad.
They'll never see us coming.
[laughter]
They really think we're just Democrats.
That ad counts on Michigan voters being
morons.
I I have a hard time believing that so
many Republicans are so stupid as to not
know that there's a difference between
between communism,
socialism, and democratic socialism.
Anything that is not Republican to so
many of these Republicans is communism.
Okay? Bernie Sanders is not a communist.
He's a socialist, a democratic
socialist, which really is capitalism
light.
Democratic socialism
um
supports a robust social safety net.
I've told this story before that I was
sitting next to an old woman well into
her 80s uh at a dinner one night. It was
uh at a relative's house and she was
watching Fox News. It was a whole bunch
of relatives over. She had Fox News on
and she turned to me and she said, "I
think the country is turning into a
socialistic state." And I thought,
"Okay, I'm going to have some fun with
this old lady." And I said, "I agree. I
think we should we should do away with
this socialism and we should start with
social security because after all, what
is social security but welfare for old
people who were either too stupid or too
lazy to save for their own retirements?
And she's like, "That's not at all what
I was talking about." And I said, 'But
social security is socialism.
So is public education.
So is the interstate highway system,
Medicare, Medicaid. It's all socialism,
but it's not communism.
And Mike Rogers wants people to think
that it is. Mike Rogers is hoping people
are stupid
or reactionary.
There's a far more serious issue going
on here, too. Far more serious. And I'd
like to play another clip. Uh this is
from a mosque in Dearbornne, Michigan.
Dearborn is a very heavily Muslim um
city. JB, do we have that clip?
gathered here today to commemorate the
martyrdom
of the great leader of our time.
We might believe this was an attack led
by Zionist Jews, but the commander of
their mission is the very one who is
trying to prove that Adam was not worth
prostrating to.
Eliss
is the one behind the scenes leading
their camp in the shadows lurking irking
in their symbology, their ideologies,
their psychology, their economy,
claiming they follow the laws of Moses
and Deuteronomy, a priest is the hidden
commander of today's society. Regardless
of the stoogge we put at the desk of the
Oval Office, Republican or Democrat, or
even if a thousand elections come to
pass, it is clear that this country was
built for and built by the Epstein
class.
And that just like Palestine, we live on
stolen land.
So, this is kind of an ongoing theme in
in some of the mosques in not just
Michigan, but we we hear this kind of
thing in New Jersey and in uh New York
City as well. Um, occasionally it will
crop up in Texas as well. Um, listen,
the truth of the matter is there are
radicals and reactionaries
in every one of the three major faiths
in the United States. every every one of
the three.
And all of us, I think, are compelled to
oppose radicalism, no matter where it
comes from. There's no room for hatred
in America. There's no room for hatred
in American politics. And it's because
we really are a melting pot. Somebody
corrected me once when I said that we
were a melting pot, saying we're not a
melting pot. We're a tossed salad. So,
we all maintain our independence, but we
sort of get the coating of the dressing
on us from other cultures. I disagree
with that. I think actually that's
dangerous. I think we really do need to
be a melting pot. There is something
that's uniquely American and I think
that's something that all of us should
embrace. I want to thank you again for
joining us and I want to thank you again
for these just remarkable numbers.
Please, please, please continue to to
watch, to share, to talk about the
podcast, to uh to subscribe. It means so
much to us. And and I've said it before,
I'll say it again. We just cannot do
this without you. And we're only
succeeding because of you. So, thank you
again. I'm John Kuryaku and this has
been the briefing